<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-23T04:05:53-02:30</updated><id>https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Narmada M Balasooriya</title><subtitle>Personal academic website</subtitle><author><name>Narmada Balasooriya</name></author><entry><title type="html">Houston, The Eagle Has Landed - About the Computer that took Man to the Moon</title><link href="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2016/09/04/houston.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Houston, The Eagle Has Landed - About the Computer that took Man to the Moon" /><published>2016-09-04T00:00:00-02:30</published><updated>2016-09-04T00:00:00-02:30</updated><id>https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2016/09/04/houston</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2016/09/04/houston.html">&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;object type=&quot;text/html&quot; data=&quot;https://viewer.joomag.com/gauge-newsletter-september-2016/0264672001478797703&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;overflow:hidden;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Narmada Balasooriya</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="article" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Most Famous Cipher Machine of All Time - The Enigma</title><link href="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/11/30/The-Most-Famous-Cipher-Machine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Most Famous Cipher Machine of All Time - The Enigma" /><published>2015-11-30T00:00:00-03:30</published><updated>2015-11-30T00:00:00-03:30</updated><id>https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/11/30/The-Most-Famous-Cipher-Machine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/11/30/The-Most-Famous-Cipher-Machine.html">&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;object type=&quot;text/html&quot; data=&quot;https://gaugeuop.wordpress.com/2015/11/30/the-most-famous-cipher-machine-of-all-time-the-enigma&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;overflow:hidden;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Narmada Balasooriya</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="article" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to become a Watch mender?</title><link href="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/09/06/watchmender.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to become a Watch mender?" /><published>2015-09-06T00:00:00-02:30</published><updated>2015-09-06T00:00:00-02:30</updated><id>https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/09/06/watchmender</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/09/06/watchmender.html">&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;
Tik tok tik tok.. The clock runs. Seconds into minutes. Minutes into hours. Hours into days. Days into years.. Every human being lives with time. Day or night, time is very important. The world is a big clock. A clock of small watches. This very big clock goes on and on and never ends. But how it does never end? Watch is a small timepiece that keeps everyone busy with going big clock. Everyone has got their own watch. Some got expensive brands while others got normal ones. Some don't have any. They use clocks on display. Some live with stolen watches. But somehow all of them have watches.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There are people who make watches. Some make expensive ones, for the rich. Some make for the normal. But there are watchmakers who make watches for the rich and the normal. Somehow they rule the people who wear watches. Leaders are like watchmakers. Some work only with the rich. Some with the poor. But there are leaders who know how to work with everyone. They makes watches for rich, normal, poor and they place clocks for those who can't buy a watch. Such are the greatest.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But apart from watchmakers and those who wear watches, there is an unseen, infamous, silent group. They are the watch menders. They repair every kind of watch. Watches of famous brands, watches of normal brands, watches of low quality, watches with different technologies etc. The watch mender has a set of simple tools, a small shop, a small house but with a talent that most of others do not possess. They know how to mend a watch or even a very big clock..
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The healers of the world are like watch menders. If the world is a big clock of thousands of small watches, the watch menders are those who repair this big clock. As a watch mender repairs a broken watch, the healers help the broken hearts with need. They are silent, soft hearted, kind and caring. They handle people with care like watch menders repair watches with care. They don't have big houses, luxurious vehicles or smart technologies. But like watch makers work with everyone, they are loved by everyone, rich and poor. Those healers reside in peoples' hearts as silent heroes. Every time the big clock starts to break apart they get together and mend it. That's how the world clock still runs. They never make a new clock even though they can. Because they love repairing broken rather than making new. And they never get tired of repairing watches.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But the most difficult task is to become a watch mender. You should know about every type of watches and how to mend them all. But being a watch mender is worth a try. At least you can mend few brands. You can become a part of the menders of the big clock. That's an honor for a lifetime.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So try to become a watch mender in the coming year and never give up on trying. Once you turn back you'll see how many watches you've mended.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Narmada Balasooriya</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="article" /><summary type="html">Tik tok tik tok.. The clock runs. Seconds into minutes. Minutes into hours. Hours into days. Days into years.. Every human being lives with time. Day or night, time is very important. The world is a big clock. A clock of small watches. This very big clock goes on and on and never ends. But how it does never end? Watch is a small timepiece that keeps everyone busy with going big clock. Everyone has got their own watch. Some got expensive brands while others got normal ones. Some don't have any. They use clocks on display. Some live with stolen watches. But somehow all of them have watches. There are people who make watches. Some make expensive ones, for the rich. Some make for the normal. But there are watchmakers who make watches for the rich and the normal. Somehow they rule the people who wear watches. Leaders are like watchmakers. Some work only with the rich. Some with the poor. But there are leaders who know how to work with everyone. They makes watches for rich, normal, poor and they place clocks for those who can't buy a watch. Such are the greatest. But apart from watchmakers and those who wear watches, there is an unseen, infamous, silent group. They are the watch menders. They repair every kind of watch. Watches of famous brands, watches of normal brands, watches of low quality, watches with different technologies etc. The watch mender has a set of simple tools, a small shop, a small house but with a talent that most of others do not possess. They know how to mend a watch or even a very big clock.. The healers of the world are like watch menders. If the world is a big clock of thousands of small watches, the watch menders are those who repair this big clock. As a watch mender repairs a broken watch, the healers help the broken hearts with need. They are silent, soft hearted, kind and caring. They handle people with care like watch menders repair watches with care. They don't have big houses, luxurious vehicles or smart technologies. But like watch makers work with everyone, they are loved by everyone, rich and poor. Those healers reside in peoples' hearts as silent heroes. Every time the big clock starts to break apart they get together and mend it. That's how the world clock still runs. They never make a new clock even though they can. Because they love repairing broken rather than making new. And they never get tired of repairing watches. But the most difficult task is to become a watch mender. You should know about every type of watches and how to mend them all. But being a watch mender is worth a try. At least you can mend few brands. You can become a part of the menders of the big clock. That's an honor for a lifetime. So try to become a watch mender in the coming year and never give up on trying. Once you turn back you'll see how many watches you've mended.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview with Dr. Roshan Ragel</title><link href="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/09/03/interview.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview with Dr. Roshan Ragel" /><published>2015-09-03T00:00:00-02:30</published><updated>2015-09-03T00:00:00-02:30</updated><id>https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/09/03/interview</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://narmadabalasooriya.github.io/post/2015/09/03/interview.html">&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;object type=&quot;text/html&quot; data=&quot;https://viewer.joomag.com/gauge-newsletter-september-2015/0912628001448992957?short&amp;amp;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;overflow:hidden;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Narmada Balasooriya</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="interview, article" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://placehold.it/750X300?text=Header+Image" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>